Guide to the Arthur Judson Brown Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, 1890-1962; Series III
  The material in this series is contained in three boxes. Box 14: The contents of this box are organized alphabetically according to form. (e.g., addresses, articles, etc.) The material within each folder is arranged chronologically. Box 15, 16: Box 15 contains the edited draft of Arthur J. Brown's autobiography, Memoirs of a Centenarian, arranged according to chapter. The unedited draft of the work is located in Box 16, also arranged according to chapter.
  - Addresses by Dr. Brown: to the "General Assembly of 1899", at the close of N.Y. Ecumenical Conference in Carnegie Hall, to the "General Assembly of 1906" to the "Sons of the Revolution", 1899,1900, 1906, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Addresses Re: Birthdays, 1955-1962 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Address by William N. Wysham Re: Memoirs of A Centenarian, Remarks by Arthur J. Brown Re: Who's Who in America, 1957, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Addresses Welcoming Dr. Brown to China and Syria, 1901, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Articles: "The Tragedy of The North Pacific Coast", no title, c. lS90, lS99 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - A Reading Journey Through Korea, 1905
  - Article: "Sir Robert Hart, 'The Wizard Of The East'", c. 1905 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Articles: "The Union Of Churches", "Six Reasons Why A Progressive Republican Will Vote For Wilson", c. 1915, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Articles: "The Immigration Bill", no title, 1924, c. 1957 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Article: Re: Arthur J. Brown, printed in "The Phi Gamma Delta", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Essay: "The Fallen Premier" - Wabash College, Baldwin First Prize Oration, 1880 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Poems, 1930-1933, 1952,1958-1962 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Prayers, 1947, 1951-1958 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Prayers, 1960-1969, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Prayers: Original form - for "Laymen's National Committee", c. 1957 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Tribute: "The Death of John R. Mott" presented to The Church Peace Union, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "Toasts" Re: Birthdays, 1959, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, incl. "Notes used in speeches", 1906,1916, 1925,1930,1932, 1955-1957, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Memoirs of a Centenarian - edited draft, foreword, Ch. "I" (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Ch. "II" (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Ch. "III" (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Ch. "IV" (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Ch. "V" (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Ch. "Vl" (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Ch. "VII" (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Ch. "VIII" (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Ch. "IX": "Some Crowned and Uncrowned Heads" (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Ch. "IX": "Do Armaments Prevent War?" (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Ch. "XI": "The Korea War And Its Threat To World Peace" - copy 1, part 1 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Ch. "XI": "The Korea War And Its Threat To World Peace" - copy 1, part 2 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Ch. "XI": "The Korea War And Its Threat To World Peace" - copies 2, 3 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Ch. "XI": "Religious Faith and Experience - 1 The Bible, Sin, Man and God" (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Ch. "XII": "Religious Faith and Experience - 2 The Basis of Our Faith" (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Ch. "XIII": "Religious Faith and Experience - 3 Immortality" (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Ch. "XIII": "Some Crowned and Unerowned Heads I Have Known" (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Ch. "XIV": "Retirement and Subsequent Activities" (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Ch. "XIV": "Change Brings Hope" (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Memoirs - edited draft Ch. ("XV"?) (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Ch. I,XVI (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Ch. "XVIII" (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Fragment, Note Re: Memoirs written by Dr. Brown (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Memoirs - unedited draft Title Page, Foreword, Table of Contents, Ch. "I" (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Ch. "I" pp. 10-11, 1-8, 13-15 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Ch. "II" (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Ch. "III" (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Ch. "IV" (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Ch. "V" (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Ch. "VI" (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Ch. "VII" (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Ch. "VIII" (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Ch. "IX" (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Ch. "X" (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Ch. "XI" (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - Ch. "XII" (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Ch. "XIII" copy 1 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Ch. "XIII" copy 2 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Ch. "XIV" (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Ch. "XV" (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Ch. "XVI" (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - Ch. "XVII" "Some Observations on Democracy" (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - Ch. "XVII": "Religious Experience - A Quest For Certainty" (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - Ch. "XVIII", one page (Box 16, Folder 61)
  - Ch. "XVIII", (one letter included) (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - Ch. "XIX": "Religious Experience", two pages (Box 16, Folder 63)
  - Ch. "XIX": "Religious Faith - A Quest for Certainty" (Box 16, Folder 64)
  - Ch. "XX" (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Ch. "XXI" (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - Ch. "XXII" (Box 16, Folder 67)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1894-1962; Series IV
  This section contains a variety of material organized alphabetically according to form. (e.g., instructions, invitations, etc.)
  Photographs, which comprise the bulk of the series, are located after the other material. Photographs of foreign countries are arranged alphabetically according to the name of the country. They are followed by personal photographs and one tape recording.
  - Bio. Info, Re: Brown Family, Grave of Edwin T. Brown (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Bio. Info. Re: Marsh Family (incl. 2 letters) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Bio. Info. Re: Thomas Family (incl. 1 letter) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Calling Cards (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Calling Cards, incl. that of Yuan Shih-kai (in Chinese, with translations) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Certificates and Credentials (see also: Oversize Material - Degrees and Certificates) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Certificate: from Greek Gov't. - Royal Order of George the First (with corres.) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Certificate: from Siamese Gov't - Order of the White Elephant (with corres.) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - College Commencement Programs Re: Conferring of Honorary Degrees to Dr. Brown (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Copy of 1791 Will of William B. Blackmore (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Instructions Re: Funeral Arrangements for Dr. Brown; Printed Acknowledgement Re: Death of Jennie Brown (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Invitations, Menu (1899-1902) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Invitations, Menu (1906) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Invitations, Menus, Guest Lists, Etc. ( 1909-1936) (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Invitations, Menus, Guest Lists, Etc. (1944, 1955-1960) (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Invitations, Programs, Guest Lists, Etc. (1961, 1962, n.d.) (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Letters of introduction from: Wm. McKinley, John Hay, Phelps Dodge, John Fowler, Samuel B. Capen, John W. Foster (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Letters of introduction: response to a letter of John Fowler by an unknown Chinese official (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Maps: Petersburg, Va., "Part of Shantung showing F.H. Chalfant's Itineraries 1897" (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Note from Thomas Royal, with autograph of Horatius Bonor (1894) (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Notes Re: Dr. Brown's Health Examinations (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Organizational Letterheads (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Passport from Manila, P.I. (see also: Oversize Mat. - Travel Documents) (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Receipt from Trans-Siberian Railroad (1909) (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Misc. incl: Memoirs of a Centenarian material, Sacred Herb from Grave of Confucius (1901), etc. (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Misc. (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Photographs: Arabia (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Photographs: Burma (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Photographs: China (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Photographs: China (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Photographs: China (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Photographs: China (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Photographs: China (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Photographs: Egypt (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Photographs: India (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Photographs: Japan (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Photographs: Korea (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Photographs: Malaysia (Singapore) (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Photographs: Palestine (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Photographs: Philippines (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Photographs: "Siam" (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Photographs: "Siam" (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Photographs: "Siam" (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Photographs: Sweden (Box 19, Folder L4)
  - Photographs: Syria/Lebanon (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Photographs: "Our visit to Budapest" (photo album) (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Photographs: Enclosures from the photo album "Our visit to Budapest" (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Photographs: Countries incl - Austria, Indo-China (Viet Nam), Turkey, etc., unidentified (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Photographs: Postcards from England, Sweden, Turkey (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Photographs: Group Photos from European Conferences (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Photographs: Robert E. Speer, Nicholas de Hortley, Two French Army Chaplains, Stephen (Archbishop) (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Photographs: Tintype of Edwin T. Brown in Civil War Uniform (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Photographs: Arthur J. Brown (1880-1906) (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Photographs: Arthur J. Brown (1925-1937, 1949) (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Photographs: Arthur J. Brown (1955-1959) (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Photographs: Arthur J. Brown (1960-1962) (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Photographs: Arthur J. Brown (n.d.) (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Tape Recording of Dr. Brown on his 105th Birthday (Box 19, Folder 58)
- Printed Materal, 1884-1963; Series V
  All the material in this series is arranged in chronological order.
  The final two folders of the section 'magazine and Newspaper Clippings" contain book reviews written by Arthur J. Brown for The Interior, circa 1885 to 1887. These clippings are arranged alphabetically according to the title of the book being reviewed. Material in the section "Re: Publications" is arranged according to the first publication date of each work. On the folder heading, this date appears in parenthesis next to the title. (e.g., New Forces in Old China (1904)). Material within each folder is arranged chronologically.
  - Magazine and Newspaper Clippings, 1884-1919 (Box 20, Folder 1-30)
  - Magazine and Newspaper Clippings, 1920-1963, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 31-59)
  - Magazine and Newspaper Clippings: Book Reviews written by Arthur J. Brown for The Interior, ca. 1885-1887 (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - A-H (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - I-W (Box 21, Folder 61)
  - Minutes and Reports, 1890-1963 (Box 22, Folder 62-73)
  - Pamphlets and Notices, 1891-1962 (Box 22, Folder 74-85)
  - Pamphlets: Addresses, 1894-1956 (Box 23, Folder 86-90)
  - Pamphlets: Sermons, 1891, 1911, 1925, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 91)
  - Re: The New Era in the Philippines (1903) (Box 23, Folder 92)
  - Re: The New Era in the Philippines (1903), 1904, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 93)
  - Re: New Forces in Old China (1904), 1904-1905 Jan (Box 23, Folder 94)
  - Re: New Forces in Old China (1904), 1905 Feb-1906, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 95)
  - Re: The Foreign Missionary (1907), 1907-1908, c. 1930, 1932, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 96)
  - Re: The Foreign Missionary (1907): "Le Missionaire Et Son Oeuvre" from Le Chretian Belge (with translation), 1911 Feb 4 (Box 23, Folder 97)
  - Re: The Nearer and Farther East (1908) (Box 23, Folder 98)
  - Re: The Why and How of Foreign Missions (1908), 1908-1910, 1921, 1935, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 99)
  - Re The Chinese Revolution (1912)., 1912 May-Jul (Box 23, Folder 100)
  - Re: The Chinese Revolution (1912), 1912 Aug-Nov, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 101)
  - Re: Rising Churches in Non-Christian Lands (1915) (Box 23, Folder 102)
  - Re: Unity and Missions (1915), 1915-1916, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 103)
  - Re: Russia in Transformation (1917), 1917-1919, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 104)
  - Re: The Mastery of the Far East (1919), 1919 Apr-Jul (Box 23, Folder 105)
  - Re: The Mastery of the Far East (1919), 1919 Aug-1920, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 106)
  - Re: The Expectation of Siam (1925) (Box 23, Folder 107)
  - Re: Japan in the World of Today (1928) (Box 23, Folder 108)
  - Re: One Hundred Years (1936), 1937, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 109)
  - Re: Memoirs of a Centenarian (1957), 1958, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 110)
  - Church Bulletins and Newsletters, 1903 -(1914-1929)- 1947 (Box 23, Folder 111)
  - Church Bulletins and Newsletters, 1965, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 112)
  - Bound Material: Bible Belonging to Arthur J. Brown, with enclosures (Box 24, Folder 113)
  - Bound Material: Philips' Authentic Map of Asia (Box 24, Folder 114)
  - Bound Material: Map of the Far East, c. 1907 (Box 24, Folder 115)
- Restricted Circulation and Oversize Material, Series VI
  Restricted circulation material contains original copies of frail materials. Use copies are available in the previous series. The material is arranged in series order, identical to the non-restricted materials
  - Restricted circulation
    - Correspondence, 1907, 1922, 1936, 1955, 1956, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Writings, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Printed material: Magazine and newspaper clippings, 1884-1963, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3-16)
    - Printed material: Minutes and reports, 1926, 1929 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Printed material: Re. publications, 1903, 1907, 1908, 1911 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Printed material: Re. publications, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Printed material: Re. publications, 1915, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Oversize Material
    - Degrees and Certificates:
      - Carroll College, 1916 (Box OV1)
      - Lake Forest College, 1891 (Box OV1)
      - Lane Theological Seminary, 1883 (Box OV1)
      - Wabash College, 1880, 1886 (Box OV1)
      - Yale University, 1913 (Box OV1)
      - "Oregon National Guard...appointed and constituted... Captain and Chaplain of the 1st Regiment of Infantry, 1889 (Box OV1)
      - Wabash College - Alumni Award of Merit, 1951 (Box OV1)
      - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, 1960 (Box OV1)
    - Photographs:
      - "Testimonial Dinner...tendered by The American Committee on Religious Rights and Minorities and The Church Peace Union, 1936 (Box OV1)
      - "Delegates to the annual meeting of the North American Section of the World Alliance of Presbyterian and Reformed Churches" with President Coolidge in front of the White House, 1936 (Box OV1)
    - Travel Documents:, 1925
      - Issued at "Tokio", Japan, 1901 (Box OV1)
      - Issued at Chefoo, China, 1901 (Box OV1)
      - Issued at Cairo, Egypt, 1902 (Box OV1)
      - Issued at Egypt with fragment, (1902?) (Box OV1)
      - Issued at Constantinople, 1902 (Box OV1)
      - Issued at Washington, 1909 (Box OV1)
      - Issued at Korea [missing], n.d. (Box OV1)
      - Issued at Siam, n.d. (Box OV1)
    - Other:
      - Korean Alphabet (Box OV1)
      - Life and Work - Daily Bulletin of Universal Christian Conference at Stockholm - containing address given by Arthur J. Brown, 1925, Aug. 20 (Box OV1)
      - Color woodcut placard related to Boxer Rebellion with handwritten caption: "Boxer Picture Placard (falsely representing the driving out of the foreign troops from Peking) Distributed in Shantung winter 1900-01" (Box OV-d15)